Guide to the John H. White papers, 1854-1877.
White, John H. papers, 1854-1877.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John H. White papers, 1854-1877.
1988
John H. White, 1821-1877.
.3 cubic ft.
A photograph album, scrapbooks, pamphlets, photographs, broadsides, postcards, and greeting cards.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes a photograph album of officers and members of the 1870 New York State Assembly, scrapbooks, pamphlets, photographs, broadsides, postcards, and greeting cards.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John H. White was a lawyer, apparently originally from Jamestown, New York. He had a law office at 169 Broadway, New York City, and lived at 32 West 35th St. He served in the New York State Assembly at its 93rd Session, 1870 and died in March 1877 or somewhat earlier.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes a photograph album of officers and members of the 1870 New York State Assembly, scrapbooks, pamphlets, photographs, broadsides, postcards, and greeting cards.
SUBJECTS
Names:
White, John H., 1821-1877.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly.
Subjects:
Lawyers--New York (State).; Legislators--New York (State).
Places:
New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1950.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- The Knickerbocker Gallery (New York: Samuel Hueston, 1855 ) (Box 1)
  Is "A Testimonial to the Editor of the Knickerbocker Magazine from its Contributors. With forty-Eight Portraits on Steel, from Original Pictures Engraved Expressly for This Work." Is inscribed "A Christmas memento to my Wife - John H. White, Dec. 25, 1854." Bound vol. [cover loose].
- Unidentified photograph, presumably of Civil War general, removed from above book. D. Appleton & Co., Publishers, 1861. (Box 1)
- 1 sheet of historical notes on French exploration and settlement from 1534, n.d. (Box 1)
- Pamphlet: "Speeches Delivered at the Republican Union Festival, in Commemoration of the Birth of Washington; Held at Irving Hall, Feb. 22, 1862, under the Auspices of the Republican Central Committees, of the City and County of New York." (New York: G.P. Putnam, 1862 ). 27 pp. (Box 1)
- Photograph album, leather bound with clasps, containing portraits, some autographed, of members of the New York State Legislature, ca. 1870. (Box 1)
  Also contains pictures of Governor John T. Hoffman [elected 1868], Lt. Gov. Allen C. Beach, Secretary of State H.A. Nelson, and Comptroller W.F. Allen (p. 1). 195 photographs, 150 of which are autographed.
- Resolutions of Kane Lodge, No. 454, made on the death of John H. White. (Masonic Lodge). Unpaged bound vol. New York City, Mar. 6, 1877. (Box 1)
- Plate for steel engraving of Samuel Barrett. (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, chiefly on foreign affairs, Franco-Prussian War, etc. 1870's. Some loose clippings. (Box 1)
- Removed from above scrapbook and added to greeting card collection, 2 Christmas cards: "The Dead Sea" and Bible verses, 1883; Purple morning glories, n.d. (Box 1)
- Six Concord, Mass. postcards. -- Added to Postcard Coll.
- Envelope with picture of Old Wright Tavern, Concord. -- Added to Letterheads.
- Broadsides
  - Resolutions offered by John H. White, 1875 or later. Br.#____ Card entry: "Politics (New York State)"
  - WEST SIDE ASSOCIATION. To owners of West Side real estate, n.d. Br.#____ Card entry: "Real estate (New York City)"
  - Notice of Henry T. Kneeland & Co., grain commission merchants of N.Y.C., 1889. Br.#____ Card entry: "Commission merchants"
- Letter from Laura M. King, Ridgefield, New Jersey, to her cousin, Bella Fuller (Mrs. Charles G. Fuller), Evanston, Illinois, Nov. 17, 1907, concerning three enclosed photographs of the wife and son and daughter of their uncle, Charles F. King of San Antonio, Texas, taken in 1865. Photograph of Mrs. King added to Fashion Collection, dated women's fashions box, and those of children to same, dated children's fashions. (Box 1)